# **Anupama Ojha**

Data analysis, Business Development, Project Analyst and AI/ML.

Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh 462023

anupamaojha.cs12@gmail.com

+91 96085 96033

To be a part of an organization where I can grow in terms of knowledge, skills and attitude and put my best to learn new trends and new environmental skills, and if given a chance to work with you, I assure you of my level best. I am new to this industry with 2 years of experience who is willing to give total support to the organization that I work for with all my capabilities that I have and that I'll learn.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth: 2020-01-31 Eligible to work in: India

**Highest Career Level:** 1-2 years' experience

Industry: Software Development (IT)

Total years of experience: 2

# **Work Experience**

#### **Data Analyst**

Netlink Software Pvt. Ltd - Mandideep, Madhya Pradesh November 2022 to Present

- Analytical understanding of data.
- Generation of reports, data Modelling, Data Migration, Data Analysis, and manipulation.
- Analytical dashboard and functional testing, manual testing.
- Dashboard development
- SQL, database (vertica), azure, AWS, RDBMs.
- Advanced Excel (VLOOKUP, lookup).
- Project management, business requirements (BRD) and KPI Mapping documents.
- Fresher Interviews, Project Presentation, Client handling etc.

#### **Trainee Python Developer**

Rack Al Pvt. Ltd - Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh March 2022 to October 2022

- I was responsible for developing and implementing functional programs in **Python** language with its libraries like **pandas**, **NumPy**, **skit-learn**, **(keras**, **TensorFlow)**.
- In this role, I had to do teamwork with developers to design algorithms and flowcharts.
- Along with this, I integrate several software components and **third-party modifications** in the existing program are also observed by me.
- I had to create technical documentation for reference and reporting.

#### • Data visualization with JustPy

#### Internship

NRI Institute of Technology - Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh July 2021 to December 2021

Project work based on **Data Analytics and Visualization**.

- Skill: SQL, python, data visualization and analytics, excel, Functional testing etc
- Interview Preparation, Presentation skills, et

# Skills / IT Skills

- Communication Skills, Presentations, Client Handling
- SQL, Microsoft Excel Advances Analysis skills
- Python
- Pandas, NumPy, Skit-learn Lib
- Django
- Rest API, Keras, TensorFlow
- Data mining
- Communication skills
- Tableau, Power BI tools
- Machine learning
- Natural language processing
- Computer vision
- Big data, Hadoop
- Interview Scheduling, Project Management
- Functional testing
- Data analytics
- Artificial Intelligence
- Simple Chatbot
- Data analysis skills: Data Modelling, Data Migration
- Data Manipulation

### Languages

- English Fluent
- Hindi Fluent
- Bengali Fluent

### **Online Profile**

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anupama-ojha-12b055199

### **Certifications and Licenses**

#### **Sentimental Analysis**

October 2022 - Feb 2023

(Client- Netlink Software's)

Sentiment analysis projects involve using **natural language processing (NLP)** and **machine learning** to analyse and categorize text based on **sentiment**. The goal is to gain insights from data like social media posts or customer reviews. Steps include **data collection, pre-processing, feature extraction, model training,** and **evaluation**. Success depends on **data quality, pre-processing** techniques, and choice of **algorithms**. Applications include social media monitoring, brand management, and market research.

#### **Data Analytics and visualization**

February 2023 – April 2023

(Client- Netlink Software's)

Data visualization is the graphical representation of information and data. By using visual elements like charts, graphs, and maps.

The Data analysis and visualization project using **Python and JustPy** involves using Python and the JustPy library to analyse and visualize data. It includes steps like **data collection**, **data preparation**, **data analysis** using libraries like **NumPy and Pandas**, **data visualization using JustPy** and other visualization libraries, creating interactive **web-based visualizations**, and deploying the web application. This project enables the exploration and communication of data insights through interactive and visually appealing web-based visualizations.

#### **Web Scraping**

March 2022 – September 2022

(Client- Rack AI Pvt. Ltd.)

Web scraping is a process of **automating the extraction of data** in an efficient and fast way. With the help of web scraping.

Web scraping of images involves automatically extracting images from websites developed with **Python, BeautifulSoup, Scrapy, Selenium, Pillow, Pandas, Requests**. It includes steps like identifying the target website, **parsing the HTML structure**, **fetching**, and **parsing web pages**, locating **image URLs**, downloading the images, and optionally performing **image processing**. The scraped images can be stored and managed for various purposes, such as building datasets or creating image galleries. Legal and ethical considerations should be considered during the process.

#### **Communication Skills**

October 2020 – Feb 2021

(Client-LinkedIn)

It recognizes successful completion of a comprehensive program designed to enhance and refine **communication abilities**. This certificate validates the individual's competence in various aspects of effective communication, including **verbal** and **nonverbal** communication, **active listening, public speaking, interpersonal skills**, and **conflict resolution**.

#### **Education**

### Bachelor's in Technology, Computer Science (8.9 CGPA)

NRI Institute of information science and technology, Bhopal - Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh R.G.P.V. University, Bhopal

May 2019 to May 2023

### 12th in Science (PCM)

Rajkamal Saraswati Vidya mandir Dhanbad - Dhanbad, Jharkhand

**CBSE Board: 80%** 

March 2016 to May 2018

### **Diploma In Psychology (Human Behaviour)**

University of Strathclyde Glasgow (Online Platform)

Accuracy: 83% Grade: "A

August 2019 to September 2020

#### 10th in All subjects

SSVM Institutions Dhanbad - Baghmara, West Bengal

CBSE Board: 10 CGPA April 2015 to July 2016

### **Additional Information**

Bachelor in Computer Science with distinction and more than two year of experience as a Data Analyst. Key knowledge in **AI/ML**, data science and analytics, data structures and algorithms, and data modelling.

Proficiency in **HTML, MySQL, big data (Hadoop), Python**. Beginner in MATLAB. Experienced in manipulating visual hierarchy and automation in prediction algorithms for customer trends.

Organized, top performer, and goal-driven individual with **Eight months** of experience in working with **key stakeholders** and communicating between **manager** and technical levels of an organization. Skilled at using data modelling to build a competitive advantage.

New to corporate industry with **1.8 years of experience**, can work well under pressure and make the best of any situation. Passionate individual with great **interpersonal and communication skills**.